### JANVIER MBILIZI

Denver, CO. 80014 | Phone: 540-236-2223 | Email: janviermbilizi@gmail.com Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/janvier-mbilizi | Github: https://github.com/Janviermbilizi Portfolio: https://janvier-mbilizi.herokuapp.com/

### About Me

Full Stack Web Developer educated at the University of Denver (DU) who has a passion for approaching programming challenges from different angles. Strengths include meeting deadlines, creativity, and working as a team to create meaningful web applications. Remains calm in fast-paced environments and use my education and skill-set to solve problems or debug when code is not working as expected. Outside of Software Engineering career, has a Bachelor's degree in Geology and Mining and has worked as a Case Manager and Community Advocate serving hundreds of refugee and immigrant families across the Denver-metro and Shenandoah Valley area. Strives to adapt quickly, communicate effectively, and think critically; these strengths allow to be a team player. Quick and dedicated learner who is hoping to become an asset to your company.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript(jQuery, Node.js) and limited python.

Frameworks: front-end frameworks(Bootstrap, Materialize, Foundation, ReactJS), back-end frameworks(Express.js)

**Core Concepts:** Databases (MySQL, MongoDB), Deployment (Heroku, Github), Version Control (Git, GitLab), Quality Assurance (Writing Tests), Server Side Development (Node.js, Express, MERN Stack), Command Line, and proficiency with advanced electronics

# **Projects**

**Traveler** | Git Repository: https://github.com/Janviermbilizi/traveler | Link to Deployed Project: https://janviermbilizi.github.io/traveler/

- Description of project: Application that travelers can use to organize/prepare (with checklist) and get information(such as weather, nearest airport, attractions and more) about the place they are visiting.
- *Core responsibilities in the project*: Full-Stack Development (designed the weather and checklist card, and made API calls that get data from weather API and display them in the card depending on the City or place that the use searched for)
- *Tools/languages used*: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jquery, materialize CSS framework, Git/Github and APIs (weather, googlemap, AirportFinder and Airport info got from Rapid API).

Metabook | Git Repository: https://github.com/cwright489/Project2 | Link to Deployed Project: https://cryptic-sea-06963.herokuapp.com/

- Description of project: Application that users can use to learn about themselves through zodiacs by entering basic information.
- Core responsibilities in the project: Full-Stack Development (Managed handlebars to display data coming from APIs)
- *Tools/languages used:* HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, Lodash.js, Passport.js, Express, Git/Github, heroku and Astrology API.

entertainME | https://github.com/Janviermbilizi/entertain-me | Link to Deployed Project: https://entertainme-app.herokuapp.com/

- Description of project: Application that allows the user to follow their favorite movies, TV shows and celebrities all in one place. It allows the user to follow what interests them by favoriting and tracking new releases with the ability to share socially and see what others in the community are watching.
- Core responsibilities in the project: Full-Stack Development (Authentification, User's profile, database management, general UI).
- *Tools/languages used:* HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, MERN(MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), framework(React-Materialize), npm packages(Bcrypt, Passport, express-jwt, axios, etc...), APIs[The movie database(TMDB) and randomuser]

# Professional Experience

**Full Stack Web Developer:** Managing and working in a team as a full stack web developer for a creation of 3 full stack projects, since 2019-Current.

**Case Manager** at Lutheran Family Services (LFS), Denver CO (2018-Now): Manage and advocate for over two hundred families in the Denver-metro area. Train and manage interns throughout the year. Developed and analyzed reports.

**Assistant Case Worker** at Church World Service (CWS) Harrisonburg Refugee and Immigration Office (2017-2018 in Harrisonburg, VA): Community Advocate serving hundreds of refugee, asylee families across the Shenandoah Valley area. **Intern** at National Building and Public Works Laboratory (LNBTP) in Burundi/Africa (2016-2017): Analyzed and synthesized the geotechnic and rheumatic characteristics of materials. Developed and analyzed reports.

## Education

- Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University Of Denver (DU), Denver CO.
- -Bachelor of Science in Geology and Mining from the University of Burundi(UB), Burundi.

# Leadership and Core Skills

- -Vice President of CEG (Club of Geology students at the University of Burundi ) 2013 2017
- -Fluency in 6 languages including, French, Swahili, Kirundi, Kinyarwanda, Kinyamulenge and Chinese(Mandarin).
- Public speaking, Interpreting, translating, and Community Advocate